Hi, my name is Xenia and I'm going to
tell what is new in sustainability in
2026 release wave two. So, first of all,
if you used formulas before, now good
news, it will be also available in the
purchase order and purchase invoice. So,
you can use them in the same way as a
journal, but in the documents. Also, we
improved how you can find entries I mean
sustainability entries, of course,
through the system. So, now you will
have a similar way like for all other
entries in the system and it will be
much easier to find all the details
which you
usually finding.
Uh next very big change, it is
improvements for the value chain
emissions across the system. So, now it
will be also available in item journals,
item reclassification journal, fixed
asset reclassification journal, and
service management. Also,
for the scope three, now you will be
able to track it based on the item
tracking level.
So, what it means, you can define on the
item card if you want to use average
method or specific method.
Also, we a bit improved the ECG report
layout, so it also will be able to print
out information per lot.
Another small thing, we improved the
reversal process.
Before,
to reverse the sustainability ledger
entry, you needed to create manually the
entry with a separate
signs, let's say it like this. Now, you
have a regular reverse button like for
the general ledger entries, so you can
do the reverse in the same way.
And also small change for the
collect amount from GL function, now it
can remember what you already posted and
it will suggest you just the remaining
part to post.
Uh last, it is UDR certificate capture,
but about UDR, I will tell in a separate
video.
Before we jumping to the end-to-end
demo,
uh I want to remind you how our formulas
are set it up. So, on the screenshot,
you can see that I have a setting for
the account 13171.
Uh so, you can see that it is based on
the distance. You can see which
emissions I'm using. So, this setup is
on the sustainability account level.
And now, we are ready to jump to the
demo. So, I will show you how it works
in the system.
Okay, let's start in the purchase order.
To the purchase order, I added several
items, also a fixed asset and GL
account. So, I'm going to buy several
coffee machines and also one coffee
machine for internal usage, which will
be a fixed asset.
Uh why have the same uh thing twice?
Because I got information from the
vendor that for the first one, they used
the green energy, so the emissions will
be lower there. And for the second
batch, it was just a standard one.
So, you can see
here that
it will be different emissions.
Uh also, I use the item tracking.
Here, it will be the green lot.
And here,
it will be the standard one. For the GL
account, it will be just to record some
freight fees.
And here, I want to show you how our
formulas are working. So, as promised,
I'm using 13171.
And
as we saw,
the foundation is distance. So, I can
modify distance, but I can't modify fuel
or customer amount. So, that's good.
If I will modify it, you will see that
it will be recalculated.
Yes.
Also, you can, of course, change the
installation multiplier if, for example,
it was not the one truck, but two
trucks. So,
yeah, let's say 100.
For the fixed assets now, you also can
use emissions. You can see I also added
here some.
Um okay. So, let's post.
If we will go to the entries,
you will see sustainability value
entries,
fixed asset,
and also, you can see that we have two
records because we used different
batches
with a different emissions.
And sustainability ledger entry,
it is for our transportation.
Okay.
Now, let's imagine that we want to sell
one of those
machines.
I have a sales order, and I want to sell
the one which was the green one and the
one which was the standard one. So, we
will see how it will look like.
Let's post the order.
Let's go to the invoice.
Let's check entries first.
So, two entries.
One piece of each.
And you can see
it is a different emissions as expected.
Now, I also want to show you layout.
I will use our ESG and
we want emission basis details by item
tracking.
So, you can see that it shows for me
that it was a lot green 150
standard one 210 and
we have a total here.
Uh now, we're moving to the item
journal.
I'm going to do some positive adjustment
for some spare parts because those
coffee machines are on service and we
might need some spare parts for that.
Here, I also using different emissions.
And by the way, I'm using the serial
numbers here. So, if we will go to the
item tracking, you will see it.
So, I'm using serial number green one
green two.
And here, it will be standard.
Yes.
And just for the record,
just remember that it was 10 and 14.
Yeah.
Now, we post.
Yes.
Now, I just remember that oh, I posted
everything for the main location, but
usually when I'm doing service,
I'm taking it from the east location.
So, I can use the item reclassification
journal
to correct it.
Let's move just [snorts]
one piece for our demo.
We're moving the green 01.
And now, as expected, we have a service
order for the machine.
Yes, it is for our customer at Datum
Corporation, and it is our machine which
we just sold.
Okay, let's go to the service lines.
In the service lines, we have resource,
and we have our spare part.
We have emissions for them,
but I want to make sure that we will
have the correct
emission for our spare part. So, we are
going to use here
the green one.
So,
I'm going to post the order, and we will
check if our emissions are correct.
So, find entries.
Okay, let's check item.
And you can see it took 10, not 14. So,
it's right because as I showed you in
the journals before, for the green one,
we used 10,
for the standard one, 14, and on the
item card itself, we had um default one,
14. So, that is why you saw it in the
service order at some point, but when we
posted and linked it to the
correct item tracking,
It took the right one. Also, it's
proving that when we did the
reclassification, it also took it with
the right emissions.
Uh next part is our reversal.
Let's go to the sustainability ledger
entries.
As I promised earlier, you now have here
reverse transaction button.
So, if I will try to reverse
this one, let's see what will happen.
It not It doesn't allow it because it
was posted through the documents. So, it
is the same limitations as for the
reverse in the general ledger entries.
You can reverse
those entries which were created through
the journals.
Let's now try to reverse the journal
ones, and we can even select several of
those
and reverse.
Okay.
And now you have three new
reversal
entries.
You can see
minuses here.
You can see the column reversed.
And you can see that these entries
reversed by those three.
And this reversed
this group of entries.
I also mentioned that fixed assets are
included now.
So, you will see the emissions also in
the journals.
So, we have in the fixed assets general
journal, sustainability account, and
total CO2.
And also in the reclassification,
so in the fixed asset reclassification
journal, I want to mark that you have
reclassify CO2 percentage, so it will
work in the same way as a acquisition
cost. It will also split it by the
percentage which you will define here.
Okay, now I will tell you more about the
improvement for the collect from general
ledger.
Before it was extremely important to use
the from date to date filter, so then it
will suggest you to post
at least with this period.
And you can control it like that.
So, you see that I'm using the date
filter and now it's suggesting me
166.66.
Uh I posted it and now when I run it one
more time for the same account,
uh we can see that we have in a total
amount just a remaining part. So, net is
different, it's a total one, and what we
suggested to post it just remaining.
After we posted again, we have two
sustainability ledger entries with 83
and 166.
So, everything was posted.
I run it again uh for the same account
without date filter, and I can see the
net is 200, but in the total amount, it
is zero because system already knows
that you posted
everything, and now it's not suggesting
you to post anything.
So, that's what we prepared for you for
sustainability this time.
We continue to improve our
functionality.
See you
next week.